## **Richard Enlow Human-Centered Design**



HELLO@RICHARDENLOW.COM





(415) 912-7820 RICHARDENLOW.COM

I'm an experienced product designer (UX, UI, IxD) based in San Francisco. I'm a problem solver by heart and have embedded myself in design and technology for over a decade. I've delivered and led design efforts across diverse products and industries. I love building useful tools and delightful experiences with kind, smart people.

## **EXPERIENCE**

**Dispatch Logistics** 

CEO & Founder AUG 2017 - CURRENT Our team worked to streamline wholesale distribution, from order entry to delivery. I led user research, product design, product management, and operations, working to power up the supply chain.

**Pivotal Labs** 

**Product Designer** & Design Manager

DEC 2014 - AUG 2017

As a product designer (IxD, UX, Vis), I helped clients deliver valuable and innovative apps for their business and users. As a design manager, I coached, mentored and grew the design practice. Clients include:

Mercedes-Benz



BOEING

**Fuze** 

**Principal Product** Designer (UX/IxD) SFPT 2013 - DFC 2014

I led the design and experience for next-gen workplace collaboration platform (desktop & web). We improved the user experience and added vital features like project spaces, screen share, and onboarding.

Amoe.ba

UX/UI Designer

OCT 2012 - SEPT 2013

I helped companies build useful, intuitive products, from rapidprototyping through pixel-perfect implementation. Projects ranged from collaboration platforms to social networks. Clients include:

mozilla |





**Various** 

Web & Graphic Designer 2005 - 2012

I designed websites, emails, catalogs, advertising across online and print media both in-house and agency-based. See LinkedIn for details.

**EDUCATION** 

**Cont'd Education** 

2005 - CURRENT

Courses at Stanford, General Assembly, Nielsen Norman, UCSD, and D. School in Design Thinking, User Research, Lean Startup, Front End Dev, Human Centered Design, & Interaction Design.

CIT - Web & Graphic Design

**GRADUATED 2005** 

Founders Award Recipient, Student Mentor

## **SKILLS**

Seasoned design practitioner - User Experience (UX), Interaction, User Interface (UI), Visual, and Service Design. Experienced in user research methods both qualitative and quantitative. Background in designing for iOS, Android, Apple Watch, Responsive Web, and Desktop applications. An expert facilitator with people and practice management experience. Experienced with modern design tools; Sketch, Invision, Illustrator, etc. and front-end web technologies (HTML, CSS, JS).